# SUYASH SAHAY

suyash.macr2117@nfsu.ac.in

b0b363240

linkedin.com/in/suyash-sahay-

# **LAWYER**

My reading interests lie primarily in the fields of Historical Economics, Psychology, and Law. I've always been an advocate for helping others and global human rights. My ultimate academic goal is a Ph.D. in transnational and cross-border crime. Although Gujarat is where my parents raised me, Bhagalpur, Bihar is where I'll always consider home. Both my father have served in the military, and my mom works in the art field. During my time at the secondary school level, I focused on the business curriculum. I have a natural talent for enjoying cinema. What I do for fun is compose stories and experiment with video editing software.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Legal Intern

#### · LegalEZ, Ahmedabad

Feb 2023- March 2023 (2 months)

- 1. Extensive legal research about criminal Law.
- 2. Drafted various contracts and agreements.
- 3. Maintenance of the organization's research database.

#### ONGC Vadodara

Dec 2020 - Jan 2021 (2 months)

- 1. Intensive Legal Research about Corporate Laws.
- 2. Drafting of Various Contracts & Agreements
- 3. Ability to think creatively & Find Solutions to complex legal problems, often under time pressure and with limited resources.

#### · Parul C. Shah & Associates

Dec 2019 - Jan 2020 (2 months)

- 1. Extensive Study of the Indian Constitution, Civil Rights & Procedural Codes
- 2. Client Counselling
- 3. Problem-solving skills

# • Kaushik Bhatt & Associates

Dec 2018 - Feb 2019 (3 months), Dec 2017 - Jan 2018 (2 months)

- 1. Acquired Extensive Knowledge of the laws on criminal procedures, the rules of evidence, and the elements of various crimes.
- 2. Attention to detail to identify important issues and arguments.

# Content Writer

• Free Bird Animation

Sep 2020- Jan 2021 (5 months)

## Non-governmental Organization

• Faith Foundation Trust

Dec 2016 - Jan 2017 (2 months)

- 1. Event Manager of a Drug De-addiction Rally
- Critical thinking to analyze complex situations, identify potential solutions and make well-informed decisions.
- 3. Conflict resolution to mediate disputes and find mutually acceptable solutions.

#### **EDUCATION**

1. Masters in Criminology from NFSU, Gujarat

June 2021 - Jun 2023

- Specialization Forensic Psychology
- Dissertation Topic- 'Criminal Profiles of Convicted Indian Religious Masters'
- 2. BA.LLB (Hons) from Faculty of Law, MSU, Baroda

Apr 2016 - May 2021

- Graduated with Distinction
- Specialization Social Sciences & Languages
- Dissertation Topic- 'Measurement of Hate Speech in Indian Jurisprudence'

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English
- Hindi
- Gujarati
- German (B1 Level)

#### **WORKS & INTERESTS**

#### **Research Topics**

- Presented Proposal on TOOLBOX FOR PROFILING OF RAPE CONVICTS: DEVELOPMENT & VALIDATION at Forensic Hackathon 2023
- Presented Paper on Cyber Sexual Harrasement CYBER-SEXUAL HARASSMENT AGAINST FEMALES & ITS LEGAL FRAMEWORK IN INDIA at 13th Asian Criminology Conference

#### **Public Interest Litigation**

 Filled 13 June 2020 against Exploitation of Public Peace & Tranquality

#### Certification

- Alternate Dispute Resolution- Amity Law School, Noida
- Madhyama Poorna in Tabla from Akhil Bhartiya Gandhrva Mahavidhyalaya
- Awarded Grade B in Intermediate Drawing Grade Examination

#### Teacher

• Tutor Experiance at Faith Foundation Trust

#### Member

- Co-founder: All India Student Union
- Law Faculty Student Association

# **REFERENCES**

- Vishal Parmar, Asst Professor NFSU vishal.parmar@nfsu.ac.in
- Dr. Deepak SA, Professor, NFSU deepak.sa@nfsu.ac.in